Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/lumihuang (LinkedIn) github.com/lumi-huang (Portfolio)

Top Skills

R studio

Python

Data Analysis

Languages

English (Full Professional)
Chinese (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Financial Mathematics

Managing Big Data with MySQL

Probability

Lumi Huang

MS Biostatistics, UCLA | Actively Seeking Full-Time Data Scientist/ Analyst Position

Irvine, California

Summary

Strong problem solving and storytelling skills. 2+ years of experience in implementing statistical models using data mining and statistics methods. Proficient in Python, R, SAS and SQL. Excellent ability to communicate statistical findings to both technical and non-technical audience. Extensive experience in data manipulation, data cleaning, and data visualization. Looking to apply my knowledge and experience to make business recommendations.

Please feel free to visit my Github: https://github.com/lumi-huang

Experience

Glaukos Corporation Clinical Data Management Intern August 2019 - November 2019 (4 months) San Clemente, CA

- * Review results from statistical analyses to ensure standards are met.
- * Save hundreds of hours in data review process by creating reusable functions and codes in R.
- * Prepare and organize eCRFs for medical device clinical trials focused on transforming the treatment of glaucoma.

UCLA Fielding School of Public Health 6 months

Statistical Consultant April 2019 - June 2019 (3 months)

Los Angeles, California

- * Offered drop-in consulting on statistical issues arising in research to members of the UCLA community.
- * Provided assistance in the area such as experimental design, data management, model fitting, and data analysis using R and SAS.
- * Prepared statistical reports for grant applications.

Graduate Student Researcher January 2019 - June 2019 (6 months)

- * Utilized R and SAS to build mixed effects logistic regression models for data analysis on clustered data.
- * Cleaned and manipulated survey data. Examined and identified factors associated with HBV testing.
- * Reported statistical findings to upper management to use in making organization decisions.

UCLA Health

Graduate Student Researcher November 2017 - December 2017 (2 months) Greater Los Angeles Area

* Utilized MySQL and PHP to design and develop a user-friendly website that connects clinical expertise, basic science, and big data for translational medical research. Provided a solution for growing needs for data analytics.

UCLA Health

Research Assistant July 2016 - January 2017 (7 months)

- * Designed and developed a demo portal using PHP and MySQL. Utilized Powerpoint to summarize and present weekly project status result in front of a group of 15.
- * Prepared and organized stroke patients' electronic healthcare data for natural language processing research.

Nike

Summer Marketing Intern
July 2014 - August 2014 (2 months)

Taipei City, Taiwan

* Designed and evaluated a marketing experiment at selected Nike stores in Taiwan. Analyzed sales data by Excel to observe user behavior, and influenced marketing team through presentation of data-based recommendations.

Education

University of California, Los Angeles

Master of Science - MS, Biostatistics · (2017 - 2019)

University of California, Los Angeles
Bachelor of Science (BS), Applied Mathematics · (2013 - 2015)